Personal Information

Name: LI ZIQI Email Address: liziqi_@hotmail.com Gender: Male Current Location: Xiamen, Fujian, China

Online Profile: http://www.linkedin.com/in/liziqi/ Personal Website: https://lizq-git.github.io/Resume-CV/

Personal Profile

Stay Hungry, Stay Foolish - Steve Job

Through the overseas study experience and the multi-nation working experience from the past 2 years, I trained myself to be a highly self-motivated, task-oriented, open-minded and someone who is willing to spend extra to learn new skill-sets to meet the demands of my job.

Skills & Abilities

Language Proficiency English and Chinese (Written & Spoken)

Programming Background Java, C++, Python, and Shell

Core Competence Software Development, Team Management,

Team Communication, Self-learning

Work Experience

01.2018 - Now

Motic China Group Co., Ltd

Software Developer

Worked as a software developer in the Development Department, and mainly handle the following tasks

- Machine Learning, deep learning, convolutional neural network training course with Global Good at Seattle, Washington, USA. The following topics are covered: (13th March 2019 Now)
 - Data preparation, using annotation tool to annotated the training data, reduced existing features to avoid over-fitting.
 - Using the faster RCNN network to train on existing micro image set and a model with high score of 99% accuracy is achieved.
 - Using Mysql workbench to get familiar the database that Global good owned. (over two million of thumbnails from all over the world).
 - Learn how to handle a small set of data, such as making use of augmentation technique on the data, e.g. rotate, mirror image.
 - Learn the usage of each neural network layer.
 - Learn the usage of hyper-parameters.
 - Learn the regression technique, linear, ridge, lasso and logistic.
 - Learn the Clustering technique, Mahalanobis distance, Principal

Component Analysis (PCA), Gaussian Mixture Models (GMMs), k-means.

- Self-learning Matlab, to work on an auto-scope project with Global Good, and handle the following tasks:
 - Code Conversion, converting Matlab Code to C++ via tool Coder and hand-coding (line by line translating from Matlab to C++).
 - Develop testing script for 200 functions.
 - Develop a script to move the Coder generated files which are .cpp and .h files. (Contents has to be update when moving.)
 - Integrate the converted code with existing software.
 - Host Scrum Meeting to communicate with the team to resolve the bugs, report the progress.
 - The source code maintenance is controlled via Git.
- > Self-learning Deep Learning Tensorflow on Linux
 - Using transfer learning and re-training technique to train an image classifier to classify the types of cells.
 - Using transfer learning and re-training technique to train an object detection to detect the objects via Nvidia container.
 - A classifier was built, an accuracy of 83% is achieved.
- Using Android Studio to maintain the Android application:
 - To develop new features.
 - To fix bugs.
 - To brief the updates to the production line, and train them as the application is a release to the microscope and the customers.
 - The source code maintenance is controlled via Git.
- ➤ Using Shell Scripting to patch the software on the Linux platform remotely.
 - In order to ensure the correctness of the patch, the following steps are followed. Firstly, investigating on the bugs, secondly evaluating the workload, thirdly making the patch shell scripting and do a self-test on the patches, lastly provide the patch installation documentation, and assisting the customer with the patching.

08.2017 - 12.2017

IBM Manufacturing Solutions Pte Ltd.

Intern

Worked as a software developer in the IBM Software Department – Deployment Automation Team, and mainly using Shell Scripting to handle the following tasks:

- Self-learning Jenkins then adopted a new authentication method on IBM Jenkins Server, e.g. LDAP (Lightweight Directory Access Protocol).
- Self-learning Docker, then work with the docker containers e.g. deploy the Docker containers.
- ➤ Self-learning IBM WAS (WebSphere Application Server) and patching the server.
- > Self-learning IBM BPM (Business Process Manager) and patching the server.
- Self-learning IBM UCD (Urban Code Deployment) and use it as a tool for the deployment automation.
- ➤ Self-learning the software version control GitHub.

05.2017 - 07.2017

Motic China Group Co. Ltd.

Intern

Worked as a software developer in the Software Development Department. Mainly doing the following tasks:

- Migrate a Visual Studio 2008 based program to Visual Studio 2013 based program.
- Integrate with Motic protection mechanism, e.g. hardware dongle and software license.
- Integrate with Motic hardware, e.g. the Motic camera series.
- Get familiar with the migration of the Matlab solution to C++ language based.

08.2016 - 05.2017

Final Year Project with NTU – Monitor System for the Elderly

The main objective of this project is to develop a monitoring system to keep track of the elderly's motions through multiple sensors, based on the collected data to make a decision whether the elderly needs help or not.

- Data collection, use Arduino Uno R3 board to work with different hardware sensors then send to collected data to the laptop via the radio communication module.
- Data handling, use Visual Studio to develop required programs:
 - ◆ Client, listen to the radio communication module and handover to the server.
 - ◆ Server, store to data from the client to the SQL database and link the web application to access the database.
 - ◆ Web Application, provide the interface for the caregivers to access the collected data via account and password.

08.2015 - 11.2015

Project Manager

Gathered a team of five to provide services to a company. E.g. Android,IOS and web page development for their online ticket ordering system which is used for the bus services.

11.2014 - 06.2015

S&Z Pte Ltd.

Entrepreneur

Join a start-up software company which is launched by a friend from NTU. I played a part as a helper in recruitment and project planning.

Education			
07.2014 - 12.2017	Nanyang Technological University	Computer Engineering	Degree
03.2011 - 04.2014	Singapore Polytechnic	Info-Communication & Design	Diploma
08.2007 - 12.2010	Montfort Secondary School		GCE O Level

Awards		
2012	Singapore Polytechnic - Merit Award - Singapore Technologies Telemedia Prize	
2012	Singapore Polytechnic - Director's Honour Roll	
2013	Singapore Polytechnic - Merit Award - Hutcabb Prize	
2013	Singapore Polytechnic - Director's Honour Roll	
2014	Singapore Polytechnic - Merit Award - Singapore Technologies Telemedia Prize	
2014	Singapore Polytechnic - Diploma With Merit	
2018	Nanyang Technological University – Degree with Honours (Merit)	